Ivan Nasonov

Data Scientist

Github: NasonovIvan LinkedIn: Ivan Nasonov Email: nasonov.ia18@physics.msu.ru Mobile: +7 996 793 34 12

Summary

Physics graduate with a Bachelor's degree from MSU, currently pursuing a Master's degree. Skilled in machine learning (RL, CV, TR, RNN) for solving control problems, image recognition, and sequence classification. Published 1 article in Automation and Remote Control journal, with 2 more in progress. Completed 7 ML projects, demonstrating strong practical experience. Collaborative team player with a 2nd place win in the All-Russian Hackathon for Telegram Bots.

EXPERIENCE

Institute of Control Sciences of Russian Academy of Sciences

Moscow, RU

Data Scientist, Engineer of lab. control based on incomplete data

Oct. 2021 - Present

Python TensorFlow

o Leveraging machine learning (RL, CV, TR, RNN) for addressing control problems, image recognition, and sequence classification, with presentations at All-Russian conferences on control systems and mathematical theory of control.

GreenEco Investments

Moscow, RU

Data Analyst team

May 2021 - Mar. 2022

Climate research

• Engaged in reducing emissions, decarbonization, and forest/peat bog expansion projects while collaborating with Joint Crediting Mechanism, VERRA, Gold Standard, and Climate Action Reserve, and performing carbon market analysis.

Projects

Neural Network For Whale Detection

Moscow, RU

Python TensorFlow

Dec. 2022 - Mar. 2023

Transfer learning of the Xception network was used for recognizing and classifying whale voices using spectrograms.

ROTI Maps Daily Prediction

Moscow, RU

Python TensorFlow

Sept. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Using deep learning and Recurrent Neural Networks, daily prediction and synthesis of ROTI maps based on geomagnetic and solar indices were obtained.

Achievements

Weeklython - II place [All-Russian Hackathon]

Moscow, RU

Python | SQLAlchemy | Web UI

Aua. 2022

Developed Telegram bot for booking School Objects. The project contains CI/CD technology, Database project, IDEF0 diagram, UI/UX project in Figma.

Marusia Game Challenge - Prize-winning place [Hackathon VK]

Moscow, RU Aug. 2020

C++

Algorithmic solution finding in games for training the voice assistant Marusia of VK company.

Publications

Neural Network Algorithm for Intercepting Targets Moving Along Known Trajectories by a Dubins' Car

EDUCATION

Lomonosov Moscow State University

Moscow, RU

Moscow, RU

Master's degree in Physics

Sept. 2022 - Aug. 2024 (Present)

Lomonosov Moscow State University

Bachelor of Physics

Sept. 2018 - Jul. 2022

o Thesis: A neural network algorithm for intercepting targets moving along known trajectories by a Dubins' machine.

Additional Education

School21 – peer-to-peer coding school fostering practical learning

Moscow, RU

Coursera

Programming school

Apr. 2022 - Jun. 2024 (Present)

deeplearning.ai

Mar. 2020 - May 2020

The Deep Learning Specialization

o Subjects: Neural Networks and Deep Learning; Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization; Convolutional Neural Networks; Sequence Models; Recurrent Neural Networks

Programming Skills

• Languages: C, C++, Python, Bash

Technologies: ML, DL, RL, CV, TR, SQL, Git, LATEX, MPI for Python

Knowledge: Algorithms, Data Structures, Parallel Programming